Lee Mullican Papers
Lee Mullican Papers
1947-1971
Mullican, Lee, 1919-1998
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter, sculptor, educator. Collection includes artwork reproductions used in advertisements and for magazine covers and illustrations; articles and reviews (1950-1966); newspaper clippings (1952-1967), and exhibition catalogs and invitations (1949-1971) for group and one-person shows.
149600
Biographical History
Lee Mullican (1919-1998) was an American painter and art teacher known for his abstract and surrealist works, and an an influential member of the Dynaton Movement (1940s). Much of his work was influenced by the art and environment of the American Southwest. He received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1959 and was a member of the UCLA art faculty from 1962 to 1990.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lee Mullican Papers comprises biographical material, correspondence, artwork reproductions, and memorabilia.
Correspondence contains one note, from 1955. Artwork reproductions includes advertisements, book and magazine covers, and Mullican's work as reproduced in magazines. Memorabilia consists of articles and reviews, newspaper clippings, exhibit catalogs and invitations, posters, publicity, and various other printed materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Mullican, Lee, 1919-1998.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Exhibition catalogs.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Note, 1955 (Box 1)
- Artwork (originals)
  - “Fables” lithographs, Jan-Feb 1965; 10 lithographs, hand printed at the Tamarind Lithography Workshop; numbered set 19 of 20 (Oversize 1)
  - “Hungry Ghosts” lithographs, Nov-Dec 1964; 10 lithographs, hand printed at the Tamarind Lithography Workshop; numbered set 12 of 20 (Oversize 2)
  - Miscellaneous lithographs, 3 items (Oversize 2)
  - Miscellaneous, mostly lithographs, 12 items (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 14 items (Oversize 2)
  - Miscellaneous sketches, pencil, 1947-1964; 7 items (Oversize 2)
- Artwork (reproductions)
  - [Miscellaneous], 1947-1964 (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Articles, reviews, 1950-1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1952-1967; undated; photocopies (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs, group shows, 1957-1968; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs, one-man shows, 1949-1969 (Box 1)
  - Exhibit invitations, 1950-1971; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibit posters, 1961; undated (Box 1)
  - Publicity for book, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)